In this section we are going to talk about full body movement.
So what I mean by full body movement is from your upper body down to your lower body.
Your upper body you do not want to be timid or shy, I know it is going to feel a little silly if you do not really move your arms, but you should really be moving your arms.
And the reason you will see is that arm movement a lot, especially when the intensity increases, and let's say you come to that hill, you really want to make sure you move your arms because you are now circulating a lot of blood flow evenly throughout your body, and you are getting more oxygen into your lungs, and you are breathing in that fresh air, and blowing it back out with full body movement.
Now as far as your lower body, your legs, you want to make sure that you put most of the weight down your calves.
So you see if I was running, as I am running I am putting most of the weight on my calves and I am moving my body and I am moving my arms and my shoulders.
And breathing in through the nose and breathing out through the mouth.
And will you notice the difference the next time you run, just remember in your mind what I said.
The more that you move your arms, you are going to see yourself increasing in speed and you are going to see the increase in oxygen level compared to just standing there which does very little movement.
So you really want to make sure that you do that full body movement throughout your whole entire body especially as a cross country runner.